<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE terms SYSTEM "https://resources.jetbrains.com/writerside/1.0/glossary.dtd">
<terms>
    <term name="build-grid">
        A pool of agents used by TeamCity to simultaneously create builds of multiple projects. A build grid employs currently unused resources from multiple computers, any of which can run multiple builds and/or tests at the same time, for single or multiple projects across your company.
    </term>
    <term name="environment-variable">
        Environment variables are passed into a spawned build process as into an environment. Defined by the `env.` prefix.
    </term>
    <term name="system-property">
        System properties can be passed into build scripts of certain runners as variables specific to a build tool. Defined by the `system.` prefix.
    </term>
    <term name="configuration-parameter">
        Configuration parameters are meant to share settings within a build configuration (widely used in templates and meta-runners).
    </term>
    <term name="root-project">
        A default project at the top of the project hierarchy whose settings are available to all the other projects on the server.
    </term>
    <term name="vcs-root">
        A set of connection parameters that determine how TeamCity communicates with a VCS to monitor changes and get sources for a build.
    </term>
    <term name="build-number">
        A string identifier composed according to the pattern specified in the build configuration settings. It is displayed in the UI and passed into the build as a predefined parameter.
    </term>
    <term name="build">
        A process that performs a certain CI/CD job. Builds consists of steps executing granular operations. A build is executed according to the settings specified in its build configuration.
    </term>
    <term name="custom-build-run">
       A standalone build whose settings have been adjusted compared to its build configuration.
    </term>
    <term name="build-chain">
       A pipeline, or sequence, of builds connected by snapshot dependencies. Usually designed to continuously compile, test, and deliver a certain product or component.
    </term>
    <term name="build-configuration">
       A collection of settings of a certain type of builds that determines their steps, features, and other common parameters. It serves as a blueprint for all builds that belong to it.
    </term>
</terms>
